Trevan Lawade Young 910-797-5164

trevan.young@gmail.com https://trevanyoung.github.io/ www.linkedin.com/in/trevan-young

Clearance: Top Secret

Motivated and inquisitive Software Developer with an extensive background in technology. This includes 5 years of military service as a tactical SIGINT operator, 4 years as a Geo-Location operator for the Department of Defense, and 10 months as technical support to Microsoft Software Engineers. Currently enrolled in a 6 month Full Stack Development bootcamp at the Nashville Software School in Tennessee to expand my skills and follow my passion for using technology to assist and meet the needs of others.

Projects

Mission Transition - A web application built using Html, Css, Javascript / React, and Reactstrap. I built this particular application with the goal of assisting military veterans by presenting a list of in demand and well paying career fields in conjunction with related educational programs. Github - https://github.com/trevanyoung/ReactCapstone

Experience

Full Stack Developer, Nashville Software School, January 2019-Current

- Hands on application of OOP fundamentals and SOLID principles through group and individual projects reflecting real world business problems
- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Project management & tracking using GitHub Projects
- JavaScript fundamentals leveraging DRY, modular, readable code and reusable components
- Built single-page applications with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript libraries such as jQuery and React
- Developed software using C# in conjunction with the .net framework
- Task automation with Grunt: Linting with JSHint, and module bundling with Browserify
- Styled applications with CSS Framework Bootstrap/Reactstrap
- Practiced TDD with the Visual Studio Unit Testing Framework
- Application design through white boarding dependencies and building ERDs

- Provides Tier 1 support of hardware, systems, and applications for Microsoft employees via inbound calls and emails.
- Guides user through the hardware and software configuration to resolve issues.
- Remotes into end users machine and utilized command prompt, powershell, or scripts troubleshoot issues
- Utilized Active Directory to manager user accounts.
- Assists with troubleshooting network connection problems to allow remote employees to access the corporate network via virtual private networks for secure data transmissions.

Geo-Location Operator, Mission Essential Jul 2014-Jan 2018

- Operated collection systems to provide near real time intelligence to tactical commanders and national level customers including special operation forces.
- Applies advanced geo-location analysis techniques to targets of interest to facilitate support of given missions.
- Advises the customer on guidelines for optimal usage of collection systems.

Customer Service Representative, T-Mobile March 2014-July 2014

- Responsible for answering incoming phone calls from T-Mobile customers.
- Educated customers about their services and devices, assisting them with billing issues and placing orders for new equipment.
- Conducted troubleshooting with customers for devices such as cell phones, tablets, and WiFi hotspots that used Android, iOS, and Windows operating systems.

Signal Intelligence Analyst, United States Army June 2009-March 2014

- Collected and analyzed VHF communications with direction finding to provide on the ground reporting of enemy operations and to aid the tactical mission of maneuver units on the ground resulting in their mission success.
- Prepared intelligence reports and briefed ground force commanders.
- Operated automated data processing equipment for signal intelligence collection.
- Maintained analytical working aids and databases to support target collection.
- Performed maintenance on surveillance systems and or communication equipment.
- Deployed to combat environments and supported conventional Infantry and Special Operation Forces.

Education

- Nashville Software School, Full Stack Development Bootcamp: 2019
- Western Governors University, Information Technology: 2017-2018

Certifications

CompTIA A+